American Association Of University Women
© 2011 University of Connecticut
American Association of University Women, Connecticut Division Records.
undated, 1895-2009.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
American Association of University Women, Connecticut Division.
78.3 linear feet.
MSS19880003
The American Association of University Women (AAUW) was founded in 1886 as an organization of female college graduates. The first meeting of the Association of Collegiate Alumnae (ACA) was held in Washington, D.C. on January 14, 1886. The first Connecticut branch of ACA was formed in 1892, shortly after Yale University began admitting female graduate students. The ACA was reorganized in 1920 and on May 1 the first meeting of the Association of Collegiate Alumnae Branches and College Clubs was held. The name was finally changed to AAUW in 1954. AAUW continues to promote legal, social, educational, and economic equity for women in an attempt to move women into policy making positions in all sectors of society.
History
The American Association of University Women (AAUW) was founded by Boston University graduate, Marion Talbot, as an organization of female college graduates. On 14 January 1886, sixty-five women met in Washington, D.C., and adopted a constitution for the Association of Collegiate Alumnae (ACA).
The ACA originated the following five policies which have continued to be used throughout the organization's history: only women from qualified institutions are admitted as members; branch formation is encouraged; research is conducted through committees; distinguished persons are invited to present their research before the branches; study groups are encouraged to look at all aspects of education. These were the basic founding principles of ACA.
The first Connecticut branch of ACA was formed in 1892, shortly after Yale University began admitting female graduate students. Miss Lillian Pruden was the first president. During this period, membership was almost solely from New Haven. Because no state-wide organization existed, ACA encountered problems while working on was programs such as the solicitation of Liberty Loans, and it became apparent that reorganization was necessary. On 1 May 1920, the first meeting of the Association of Collegiate Alumnae Branches and College Clubs was held.
Membership lagged during the 1930s due to the Depression, and in the early 1940s, the organization encountered further problems caused by the travel restrictions of World War II. ACA continued its work, however, concentrating on war drives such as the collection of tin cans, paper, and aluminum. During the late 1940s, its activities focused upon the returning veterans and the consequential lowering of female enrollment in universities.
In 1954, after a series of name changes, the organization settled upon the American Association of University Women. Its goals during the 1950s were three-fold: to increase the number of female faculty; to increase focus upon children; and to offer political education in the form of legislative workshops. AAUW embarked on may social, educational, and political projects in the 1960s and 1970s. In 1974, for example, the Connecticut State Division Research Project and Endowment Fund was established, providing money to assist career and academic counseling for adults. Also, a Status of Women Committee was formed to analyze the number of women employed in decision making positions within state government.
Throughout the 1980s and 90s, AAUW has continued to promote legal, social, educational, and economic equity for women in an attempt to move women into policy making positions in all sectors of society. Furthermore, AAUW supports a strong educational system at all levels, having established an educational foundation as early as 1888, and, in 1983, a legal advocacy fund to pursue these goals.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the administrative records of the Connecticut Division of the AAUW.
Arrangement
Series I: Organization and Administration ( undated, 1902-1988 ) consists of information about the structure of AAUW. This series includes minutes and correspondence dating to the 1920s, as well as by-laws, directories, membership materials and financial information (ledgers, journals and budgets).
Series II: Programs ( undated, 1903-1988 ) records AAUW's involvement with educational, cultural and topical interests. The education files include Higher Education reports from 1972-1973, a 1941 Board of Education study, and records from the Senior Courtesy Awards. This series documents AAUW's cultural interests and international relations. Topics range from science and law to revolution in modern China.
Series III: History and Anniversaries ( undated, 1892-1980 ) includes a brief history of the national organization, a scrapbook and files on celebrations (Connecticut Division's 50th anniversary).
Series IV: Publications ( 1934-1988 ) contains press releases, copies of the national publication, Charter Oak Leader, and state newsletters dating back to 1934.
Series V: Projects ( undated, 1938-1987 ) is a diverse set of materials. Some of the projects are political in nature. AAUW's participation in election night coverage and a study on women in state government, for example. Other topics include (social) leadership workshops and the Coalition on Women's Issues; (education) Teacher of the Year and Library Projects.
Series VI: Fellowships ( 1895-1988 ) contains records of fellowships given under the following names: Alice Hamilton, Claire Fulcher, Margaret Morris, and Martha Hoag. Lists of names and three books about idealism and scholarship are included.
Series VII: Legislative Activity ( 1937-1988 ) outlines AAUW's legislative program from 1937-1938. Also included are newsletters from 1937-1986 and ERA efforts from 1951-1978.
Series VIII: Publicity ( 1941-1988 ) includes articles, brochures and photographs.
Series IX: Branches ( undated, 1912-2009 ) is arranged into seven subseries: Greenwich, Hartford, New Canaan, Orange-Milford, Other, Subject files and Scrapbooks. The series contains information on all twenty-five Connecticut AAUW branches. Included here are minutes, reports, records and scrapbooks detailing branch projects.
Series X: National ( 1951-1988 ) focuses on materials produced and distributed by the National office. The national charter, by-laws, legislative history, recruiting information and policy notes are filed here. Projects such as Leaders in Action, Civil Defense and Action for Equity can also be found in this series. The one subseries, International, contains materials from or about the international branches of the AAUW.
Series XI: Memorabilia ( undated, 1973-1981 ) contains convention banners (4 from New Canaan branch), citations and related items. The Robin was done by Joan Weaver and Doris Makris.
All series but X and XI are arranged alphabetically.
Series XII: 1993 Addendum ( undated, 1912-1992 ) consists of materials added to the collection in 1993. Arranged into four subseries: Administrative, Branches, Scrapbooks and Publications. Administrative: includes annual reports, by-laws revisions, membership information, data on the Nestle Boycott, tax information and Women in Leadership files. Branches includes files of the Clinton, Norwalk, Norwalk-Westport and Waterbury branches. Scrapbooks holds news clippings collected by the Norwalk and Waterbury branches. Publications contains a memoir by Virginia Crocheron Gildersleeve as well as a book review.
Series XIII: 1996 Addendum ( undated, 1960s-1990s )
Series XIX: 1998-2010 Addenda ( undated, 1940s-2005 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to specific Connecticut-based professional associations. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
American Association of University Women.; Professional education of women--United States.; Women college graduates--Societies and clubs--United States.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Reports.; Minutes.; Programs.; Scrap-Books.; By-Laws.; Financial Records.; Publications.; Memorabilia.; Audio cassettes.
Occupations:
Professional organization.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The collection was donated to the University of Connecticut Foundation in December, 1987. The records were transferred to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the University Libraries upon receipt.
Acquisition Information
Historical Manuscripts and Archives (now Archives & Special Collections) received the materials as a transfer from the University of Connecticut Foundation in 1987. Subsequent donations have been made directly by the historian of the Connecticut Division to Archives & Special Collections.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Organization and Administration, undated, 1902-1988
  - Annual reports, 1964-1967 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports, 1968-1969 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Annual reports, 1970-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Assessment of AAUW, 1968-1969 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Branch Annual reports, 1965-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 5-10)
  - Branch Archives, 1979-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Budget Information, 1950-1988 (Box 1:, Folder 12-13)
  - By-Laws, 1902 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - By-Laws, 1937, 1942 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of Insurance, 1978-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Checkbook Registers, 1940-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 17-22)
  - Convention folders, 1976-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 23-24)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 25-37)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 38-46)
  - Directories, 1966-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 47-49)
  - Directory of the CT Branch of the Association of Collegiate Alumni, 1908 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
  - Division Archives: History of Gift to the University of Connecticut, 1988 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - Division leader's handbook, 1976-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
  - Division lists, 1953-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
  - Division and Branch officers, 1920-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 54-56)
  - Experience notebook contest, 1961-1962 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
  - Fifty year membership, 1962-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
  - Job description manual, 1986 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
  - Ledgers, 1938-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 60-69)
  - Membership, 1983-1985 (Box 3:, Folder 70)
  - Minutes, 1920-1988 (Box 3:, Folder 71-120)
  - Mission statement, 1981 (Box 3:, Folder 121)
  - Nominating Committee reports, 1969-1984 (Box 3:, Folder 122)
  - Policy and procedures, 1958-1986 (Box 4:, Folder 123)
  - Policy sheets, 1951-1986 (Box 4:, Folder 124)
  - President's reports, 1948-1982 (Box 4:, Folder 125)
  - Program Development, 1960-1970 (Box 4:, Folder 126)
  - Program Development: Chair reports, 1964-1968 (Box 4:, Folder 127)
  - Report Forms (Box 4:, Folder 128)
    - Bridgeport (Box 4:, Folder 129)
    - Clinton-Killingworth (Box 4:, Folder 130)
    - Danbury (Box 4:, Folder 131)
    - Greenwich (Box 4:, Folder 132)
    - Guilford-Madison (Box 4:, Folder 133)
    - Greater Hartford (Box 4:, Folder 134)
    - Meriden (Box 4:, Folder 135)
    - Greater Middletown (Box 4:, Folder 136)
    - Naugatuck (Box 4:, Folder 137)
    - New Britain (Box 4:, Folder 138)
    - New Canaan (Box 4:, Folder 139)
    - New Haven (Box 4:, Folder 140)
    - New London (Box 4:, Folder 141)
    - Norwalk-Westport (Box 4:, Folder 142)
    - Old Saybrook (Box 4:, Folder 143)
    - Orange-Milford (Box 4:, Folder 144)
    - Ridgefield (Box 4:, Folder 145)
    - Southington (Box 4:, Folder 146)
    - Stamford (Box 4:, Folder 147)
    - Storrs-Willimantic (Box 4:, Folder 148)
    - Wallingford (Box 4:, Folder 149)
    - Waterbury (Box 4:, Folder 150)
  - State Training Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 4:, Folder 151)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1920-1988 (Box 4:, Folder 152-156)
- Series II: Programs, undated, 1903-1988
  - AAUW and Educational TV, 1954 (Box 5:, Folder 157)
  - AAUW position on the “Etherington Report”, 1972 (Box 5:, Folder 158)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Reports, 1973 (Box 5:, Folder 159)
  - Assorted Programs, 1962-1971 (Box 5:, Folder 160)
  - Berlin Kindergarten, 1951-1952 (Box 5:, Folder 161)
  - Board of Education Study, 1941 (Box 5:, Folder 162)
  - Branch Education Chair's Reports, 1949-1967 (Box 5:, Folder 163-168)
  - Charter Oak College, 1974-1986 (Box 5:, Folder 169)
  - Coeducation presentation (Edwina Whitney), 1937 (Box 5:, Folder 170)
  - Committee report on Mystic Oral School, undated (Box 5:, Folder 171)
  - Cultural Interests, 1964-1965, 1975-1979 (Box 5:, Folder 172)
  - Cultural Reports, 1969-1970, 1976-1977 (Box 5:, Folder 173)
  - Education Chair Letters to Branches, 1951-1952 (Box 5:, Folder 174)
  - Education reports, 1903, 1905 (Box 5:, Folder 175)
  - Educational Foundation, 1961-1987 (Box 5:, Folder 176)
  - Evaluation/Termination of Awards Program, 1971-1972 (Box 5:, Folder 177)
  - Higher Education reports, 1972-1973 (Box 5:, Folder 178)
  - How to choose a nursery school, 1951 (Box 5:, Folder 179)
  - Human Rights convention, 1967-1968 (Box 5:, Folder 180)
  - International Relations, 1973-1974 (Box 5:, Folder 181)
  - Nursery/Kindergarten age children (report), 1958 (Box 5:, Folder 182)
  - Programs, 1957-1988 (Box 5:, Folder 183-184)
  - Program Guide, 1977-1981 (Box 5:, Folder 185-186)
  - Project Re-entry, 1969 (Box 5:, Folder 187)
  - Recognition of Approved Schools, 1955-1961 (Box 5:, Folder 188)
  - Redefining the Goals of Education, 1977-1978 (Box 5:, Folder 189)
  - Senior Awards
    - Central Connecticut State College, 1956 (Box 5:, Folder 190)
    - Connecticut College, 1962 (Box 5:, Folder 191)
    - Danbury State College, 1959-1962 (Box 5:, Folder 192)
    - Saint Joseph's College, 1960-1962 (Box 5:, Folder 193)
    - South Connecticut State College, 1962 (Box 5:, Folder 194)
    - University of Bridgeport, 1960-1962 (Box 5:, Folder 195)
    - University of Connecticut, 1962 (Box 5:, Folder 196)
  - Social Studies, 1950-1960 (Box 5:, Folder 197)
  - State certification of teachers, 1911 (Box 5:, Folder 198)
  - State Education chair report, 1937-1938 (Box 5:, Folder 199)
  - Status of Women committee, 1971-1982 (Box 5:, Folder 200)
  - Summary of Educational work, 1902-1913 (Box 5:, Folder 201)
  - Support for a Master Plan, 1973 (Box 5:, Folder 202)
  - Topic Guide, 1973-1977 (Box 5:, Folder 203-204)
  - Topics
    - Families facing change, 1980-1981 (Box 5:, Folder 205)
    - Law and the citizen, 1966-1967 (Box 5:, Folder 206)
    - Managing resources for tomorrow, 1981 (Box 5:, Folder 207)
    - Science, 1966-1967 (Box 5:, Folder 208)
    - Revolution in Modern China, 1966-1967 (Box 5:, Folder 209)
    - Topic reports, 1973-1982 (Box 5:, Folder 210)
    - War activities, 1942 (Box 5:, Folder 211)
    - World problems, 1963-1966 (Box 5:, Folder 212)
- Series III: History and Anniversaries, undated, 1892-1980
  - Brief history, 1980 (Box 6:, Folder 213)
  - Connecticut Division history, 1892-1950 (Box 6:, Folder 214-215)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary, CT Division, 1970 (Box 6:, Folder 216)
  - Alice Hamilton article, 1950 (Box 6:, Folder 217)
  - Golden Jubilee, 1942 (Box 6:, Folder 218)
  - Scrapbook, 1912-1950 (Box 6:, Folder 219)
- Series IV: Publications, 1934-1988
  - Charter Oak lease, 1987-1988 (Box 7:, Folder 220)
  - Press releases, 1980-1981 (Box 7:, Folder 221)
  - State Newsletter, 1934-1969 (Box 7:, Folder 222-226)
  - State Newsletter, 1969-1988 (Box 8:, Folder 227-228)
- Series V: Projects, undated, 1938-1987
  - Auerbach Service Foundation, 1956-1976 (Box 9:, Folder 229)
  - Coalition on Women's Issues, 1973-1976 (Box 9:, Folder 230)
  - Community Living, 1941-1942 (Box 9:, Folder 231)
  - Connecticut Living, 1941 (Box 9:, Folder 232)
  - Corporate Representation, 1979-1987 (Box 9:, Folder 233)
  - Foremothers exhibit, 1976-1979 (Box 9:, Folder 234)
  - Leadership workshop, 1977-1980 (Box 9:, Folder 235)
  - Library project report, 1942 (Box 9:, Folder 236)
  - Media, 1975-1978 (Box 9:, Folder 237)
  - New England Energy Task Force, 1979-1981 (Box 9:, Folder 238)
  - Participation in Election Night coverage, 1976 (Box 9:, Folder 239)
  - Regional conferences, 1978-1982 (Box 9:, Folder 240)
  - Study of Women in State Government, 1970-1974 (Box 9:, Folder 241)
  - Survey of Country Homes, 1938 (Box 9:, Folder 242)
  - Teacher of the Year program, undated (Box 9:, Folder 243)
- Series VI: Fellowships, 1895-1988
  - Essay (Bessie Brodwell Helmer), 1895 (Box 10:, Folder 244)
  - Fellowships: Alice Hamilton, Margaret Morris, Martha Hoag, 1938-1971 (Box 10:, Folder 245)
  - Claire Fulcher International Fellowship, 1959-1979 (Box 10:, Folder 246)
  - Grants and Fellowships, 1980-1988 (Box 10:, Folder 247)
  - Names Honored, 1971-1982 (Box 10:, Folder 248)
  - Names Remembered (v. I and II), 1958-1984 (Box 10:, Folder 249)
  - State Chair reports, 1957 (Box 10:, Folder 250)
  - Volumes
    - Idealism at Work: Eighty Years of AAUW Fellowships, a report by the AAUW, 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 251)
    - Idealism at Work: AAUW Educational Foundation Program, 1967-1981, a report by Doris C. Davis (Box 10:, Folder 252)
    - Investment in Creative Scholarship, 1890-1956, by Ruth W. Tryon, 1957 (Box 10:, Folder 253)
- Series VII: Legislative Activity, 1937-1988
  - Alert Newsletter, 1972-1985 (Box 11:, Folder 254)
  - ERA, 1951-1978 (Box 11:, Folder 255)
  - Legislative program, 1937-1988 (Box 11:, Folder 256)
  - Letters and testimony, 1968-1978 (Box 11:, Folder 257)
  - Newsletters, 1973-1986 (Box 11:, Folder 258)
- Series VIII: Publicity, 1941-1988
  - Articles, 1984-1985 (Box 12:, Folder 259)
  - Brochures, 1981-1987 (Box 12:, Folder 260)
  - Division banners, 1974-1988 (Box 12:, Folder 261)
  - Feature article (CT division members), 1962-1987 (Box 12:, Folder 262)
  - Photographs, 1941-1983 (Box 12:, Folder 263)
  - Connecticut Division, 1962-1972 (Box 12:, Folder 264)
  - Resolutions, 1971-1984 (Box 12:, Folder 265)
- Series IX: Branches, undated, 1912-2009
  - Greenwich
    - Annual reports, 1923-1972 (Box 13:, Folder 266)
    - Book awards, 1972-1984 (Box 13:, Folder 267)
    - Branch leaders, 1968-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 268)
    - By-Laws, 1967-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 269)
    - Caravan, 1967 (Box 13:, Folder 270)
    - Community Involvement, 1968-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 271)
    - Education report, 1964-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 272)
    - Fellowship, 1967-1972 (Box 13:, Folder 273)
    - Fundraising, 1967-1973 (Box 13:, Folder 274)
    - Fundraising benefit, 1973-1974 (Box 13:, Folder 275)
    - Fundraising reports, 1965-1967 (Box 13:, Folder 276)
    - Greenwich benefit, 1967 (Box 13:, Folder 277)
    - Legislative, 1967-1972 (Box 13:, Folder 278)
    - Local bulletins, 1970-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 279)
    - Membership committee, 1968-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 280)
    - Minutes, 1912-1959 (Box 13:, Folder 281-289)
    - Minutes, 1960-1974 (Box 14:, Folder 290-296)
    - National conference, 1953 (Box 14:, Folder 297)
    - Paper dolls (approx. 4' high), 1982 (Box OS)
    - Policy Actions, 1952-1964 (Box OS:, Folder 298)
    - Positions taken, 1969-1973 (Box OS:, Folder 299)
    - Programs, 1972-1976 (Box OS:, Folder 300)
    - Publicity, 1948-1979 (Box OS:, Folder 301-305)
    - Scholarships, 1968-1972 (Box OS:, Folder 306)
    - Signettes, 1969 (Box OS:, Folder 307)
  - Hartford
    - Annual reports, 1981-1982 (Box OS:, Folder 308)
    - Awards, 1980-1982 (Box OS:, Folder 309)
    - By-Laws, 1972-1981 (Box OS:, Folder 310)
    - ERA correspondence, 1982 (Box OS:, Folder 311)
    - Graduation through the Dark Ages, 1959 (Box OS:, Folder 312)
    - Greater Hartford, 1980-1982 (Box OS:, Folder 313)
    - Local bulletins, 1980-1985 (Box OS:, Folder 314)
    - Membership, 1952-1969 (Box OS:, Folder 315)
    - Membership correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box OS:, Folder 316)
    - Minutes, 1941-1956 (Box OS:, Folder 317-320)
    - Name change, 1972 (Box OS:, Folder 321)
    - News clippings, 1952-1970 (Box OS:, Folder 322)
    - Photographs, 1972-1981 (Box OS:, Folder 323)
  - New Canaan
    - Branch handbook, 1987-1988 (Box 15:, Folder 324)
    - Minutes, 1970-1986 (Box 15:, Folder 325-330)
    - New Canaan, 1970-1988 (Box 15:, Folder 331)
    - Newsletters, 1970-1986 (Box 15:, Folder 332-333)
  - Orange-Milford
    - Children's books, 1980-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 334)
    - Directories, 1969-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 335)
    - Fundraisers, 1979-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 336)
    - History/publicity, 1964-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 337)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1975-1986 (Box 16:, Folder 338)
    - Orange-Milford, 1972-1985 (Box 16:, Folder 339)
    - Policy sheet/Education forms, 1984-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 340)
    - 1964-2005 (Box 2011-0055)
      - AAUW Centennial (Audio cassette), circa 1981
      - Annual meeting, 1969
      - Book and author luncheon, undated, 1998-2000
      - Board meetings, 1971-1976
      - Bulletins, 1967-1968, 1985-1987, 2000-2002
      - Directory of nontraditional undergraduate programs, 1987-1988
      - Financial reports, 1999-2005
      - Membership directories, 1994-2000
      - Minutes, 1964-1969
      - Newsletters, 1995-2002
      - Policy, undated
      - Scrapbook, 1999-2006
  - Other
    - Bridgeport, 1963-1985 (Box 16:, Folder 341)
    - Clinton, 1958-1984 (Box 16:, Folder 342)
    - Danbury, 1972-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 343)
    - Housatanic, 1955 (Box 16:, Folder 344)
    - Lower Connecticut Valley (Old Saybrook), 1972-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 345)
    - Manchester, 1978 (Box 16:, Folder 346)
    - Meriden, 1956-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 347)
    - Middletown, 1966-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 348)
    - Greater Middletown, 1978-1985 (Box 16:, Folder 349)
    - Naugatuck, 1964-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 350-351)
    - New Britain, 1964-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 352)
    - New Haven, 1962-1981 (Box 16:, Folder 353)
    - New London, 1959-1987 (Box 16:, Folder 354)
    - Ridgefield, 1970-1985 (Box 16:, Folder 355)
    - Southington-Cheshire, 1955-1960 (Box 16:, Folder 356)
    - Shoreline (Guilford-Madison), 1964-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 357)
    - Stamford, 1963-1987 (Box 16:, Folder 358)
    - Storrs-Willimantic, 1957-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 359)
    - Storrs-Willimantic, 1998-2009 (Box 2011-0054)
      - Membership directories, 2002-2009
      - Minutes, 1998-2007
      - Newsletter, 2003-2004
    - Wallingford, 1977-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 360)
    - Waterbury, 1959-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 361)
  - Subject Files
    - Branch Archives, 1979-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 362)
    - Branch Board reports, 1963-1967 (Box 16:, Folder 363)
    - Branch development, 1954-1988 (Box 16:, Folder 364)
    - Branch histories, 1940-1986 (Box 16:, Folder 365-366)
    - Branch positions taken, 1970-1985 (Box 16:, Folder 367)
    - Possible new branches, 1952-1972 (Box 16:, Folder 368)
    - Satellites, 1972-1981 (Box 16:, Folder 369)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Hartford, 1941-1966 (Box 17:, Folder 370-375)
    - Hartford, 1967-1984 (Box 18:, Folder 376-379)
    - Greenwich, 1931-1942 (Box 18:, Folder 380)
    - Meriden, 1960s (Box 18:, Folder 381)
- Series X: National, 1951-1988
  - AAUW Journal, 1962-1977 (Box 19:, Folder 382)
  - Action for Equity, 1980 (Box 19:, Folder 383)
  - Admitting men into AAUW, 1979-1987 (Box 19:, Folder 384)
  - Annual reports, 1983 (Box 19:, Folder 385)
  - Charter/By-Laws, 1971-1981 (Box 19:, Folder 386)
  - Civil Defense, 1951 (Box 19:, Folder 387)
  - Committee on Women, 1975 (Box 19:, Folder 388)
  - Convention highlights, 1953-1981 (Box 19:, Folder 389)
  - Educational Center organization chart, 1983 (Box 19:, Folder 390)
  - Fellowships, 1961-1986 (Box 19:, Folder 391)
  - Friends of the family, 1980-1988 (Box 19:, Folder 392)
  - Future of AAUW, 1972 (Box 19:, Folder 393)
  - General Director's letter, 1951-1954 (Box 19:, Folder 394)
  - General Director's letter, 1960-1968 (Box 19:, Folder 395)